(BIRDS SQUAWKING)
HICCUP: This is Berk...
the best-kept secret this
side of, well, anywhere.
Granted, it may not look like much,
but this wet heap of rock...
packs more than a few surprises.
(AIR WHOOSHING)
(BLEATING)
Life here is amazing, just
not for the faint of heart.
You see, where most
folks enjoy hobbies
like whittling or needlepoint...
we Berkians prefer...
a little something
we like to call...
dragon racing!
(PEOPLE CHEERING)
Whoo!
(BLEATS)
SNOTLOUT: Whoa! (LAUGHS)
I'm sorry, Fishlegs.
Did you want that?
Oh! (GRUNTS)
FISHLEGS: Snotlout,
that was mine!
Here you go, babe.
Did I tell you that you
look amazing today...
because you do.
Ugh. Come on, Barf. It's
starting to stink around here.
Nope.
Still hates you.
Let's blow this place, Belch!
(YELLS)
TUFFNUT: All right!
(PEOPLE CHEERING)
TUFFNUT: (LAUGHS)
Oh, yeah!
Ha-ha! That's nine
for the Twins...
Astrid lags with three.
Fishlegs and Snotlout
trail with none.
And Hiccup is...
nowhere to be found.
Hmm.
Scared him off with the big
talk, didn't you, Stoick?
What are you doing, Snotlout?
They're gonna win now.
She's my princess. Whatever
she wants, she gets.
ASTRID: Ruffnut? Didn't she
try to bury you alive?
SNOTLOUT: Only for a few hours.
HICCUP: Now, dragons used to
be a bit of a problem here...
but that was 5 years ago.
Now, they have all moved in.
And really, why wouldn't they?
We have custom stables...
all-you-can-eat
feeding stations...
a full-service
dragon wash...
even top-of-the-line fire
prevention if I do say so myself.
(CHUCKLES) It's time, Gobber.
Righty-ho.
Last lap!
(BLOWING HORN)
The Black Sheep!
Come on, Stormfly.
We can still win this thing!
(ALL CHEERING)
RUFFNUT: Come on, Barf!
TUFFNUT: Let's go!
Go, Meatlug!
ASTRID: Whoo-hoo!
FISHLEGS: Let's go!
Let's go! Let's go!
This is your big moment.
Have a nice flight!
Up, up, up!
(BLEATS)
ASTRID: No!
FISHLEGS: Yes!
Good job, Meatlug.
Here you go, darling.
Mine is worth ten.
Yeah!
The Black Sheep!
ASTRID: You guys are
fighting for Ruffnut?
I'm totally winning!
We're winning
together! (SCREAMS)
SNOTLOUT: Oh, no!
(CHEERING)
Whoo! No one can
stop me now!
Except for me. We're
attached, genius.
Quit trying to steal all my glory!
Hey!
Get them, Astrid!
TUFFNUT: It's my glory!
RUFFNUT: Always
ruining everything!
TUFFNUT: No sheep, no glory!
ASTRID: Gotcha!
(LAUGHS)
Whoa!
Astrid!
Well played! (LAUGHS) (SIGHS)
That's my future daughter-in-law!
(GRUNTS)
Excuse me.
Stormfly!
Oh!
(WEAPON CLANGS)
(ALL EXCLAIM IN SHOCK)
Whoa!
(GRUNTING)
(PEOPLE CHEERING)
That's 13!
Astrid takes the game!
(CHEERING)
HICCUP: Yep,
Berk is pretty much perfect.
All of my hard
work has paid off.
And it's a good thing, too,
because with Vikings on
the backs of dragons...
ASTRID: Whoo-hoo!
(EXCLAIMS IN SHOCK)
...the world just got
a whole lot bigger.
HICCUP: Yeah!
(SINGING) Let the wind carry us
To the clouds,
hurry up, all right
We can travel so far
As our eyes can see
We go where no one goes
We slow for no one
Get out of our way...
So what do you think, bud?
You wanna give
this another shot?
(GRUMBLES)
Toothless!
It will be fine.
Ready?
(YELLING)
Yeah!
(HICCUP YELLS)
(YELLING)
This is amazing!
No longer amazing!
Toothless!
(SHRIEKS)
Oh, no!
(SCREAMS)
(HICCUP GRUNTING) Whoa!
(SIGHS)
Whoo!
That really came out of nowhere.
(TOOTH LESS GROANING)
We have to work on your
solo gliding there, bud.
That locked-up tail...
makes for some pretty sloppy
rescue maneuvers, hey?
Ah!
Looks like we
found another one, bud.
(GRUMBLES)
Oh!
Oh, what, do you
want an apology?
Is that why you're
pouting, big baby boo?
(GRUMBLING) Well, try this on!
(GRUNTS)
Oh, you feeling it yet?
Huh?
Picking up on all of my
heartfelt remorse? (GRUNTING)
Oh, come on, come on.
You wouldn't hurt a
one-legged... (SCREAMS)
You're right! You're right!
You win. You win.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa! (LAUGHS)
He's down.
And it's ugly.
Dragons and Vikings,
enemies again...
locked in combat
to the bitter... Oh!
(GROANS)
You know that doesn't wash out.
(LAUGHS)
So, what should we name it?
"Itchy Armpit" it is.
What do you reckon, bud?
Think we might find a few
Timberjacks in those woods?
The odd Whispering Death
or two in the rocks?
Who knows? Maybe we'll finally
track down another Night Fury.
Wouldn't that be something?
(SIGHS) So, what do you say?
Just keep going?
(GRUMBLES)
(DRAGON SCREECHING)
Afternoon, milady.
Where have you been?
(CHUCKLES) Hi.
Oh, winning races, what else?
The real question is...
where have you been?
Avoiding my dad.
Oh, no.
What happened now?
Oh, you're gonna love this.
I wake up.
The sun is shining.
Terrible Terrors are
singing on the rooftop.
I saunter down to breakfast...
thinking all is right
with the world and I get...
(IMITATING STOICK)
"Son, we need to talk."
(IMITATING HICCUP) "Not now, Dad.
I got a whole day"
"of goofing off to get
started." (SNICKERS)
Okay, first of all,
I don't sound like that.
Who is this character?
And second, what is that thing
you're doing with my shoulders?
Yeah, that's a truly
flattering impersonation.
Anyway. he goes...
(IMITATING STOICK) "You're the pride of
Berk, son, and I couldn't be prouder."
(IMITATING HICCUP)
"Aw, thanks, Dad."
"I'm pretty impressed
with myself, too."
(LAUGHING) When have I ever
done that with my hands?
You just did.
Okay.
Just hold still.
(CHUCKLES) This is very serious.
(IMITATING STOICK)
"You're all grown up..."
"and since no chief could ask
for a better successor..."
"I've decided..."
To make you chief!
Oh, my gods!
Hiccup, that's amazing!
(GRUNTS) Ow!
You're gonna wear
out the spring coil.
The calibration
is very sensitive.
(DRAGONS SHRIEKING)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
Yeah...
so this is what
I'm dealing with.
What did you tell him?
I didn't. By the time he
turned around, I was gone.
Huh, well,
it's a lot of responsibility.
The map will have
to wait for sure...
and I'll need to fly Toothless,
since you'll be too busy, but...
(GASPS)
It's not me, Astrid.
All those speeches and planning,
and running the village,
that's his thing.
I think you're
missing the point.
I mean, "chief."
What an honor.
I'd be pretty excited.
I... (SIGHS)
I'm not like you.
You know exactly who you are.
You always have.
But I'm still looking.
I know that I'm not my father...
and I never met my mother...
so what does that make me?
What you're searching for
isn't out there, Hiccup.
It's in here.
Maybe you just don't see it yet.
Ugh. Ugh!
Maybe.
But you know...
there is something out there.
Hiccup... (GASPS)
Whoa!
Stay close.
What happened here?
(GROWLS) All right, easy, bud.
(GASPS) Hiccup!
MAN: Fire!
Astrid, look out!
(GRUNTING)
Hiccup!
(ALL SHOUTING)
Watch the tail!
(GRUNTS)
Tie those legs up!
Huh?
Is that what I think it is?
HICCUP: Stop!
ASTRID: Stormfly!
What are you doing?
TRAPPERS: Whoa!
Back again?
Soil my britches.
That is a Night Fury.
I thought they were
all gone for good.
It looks like our luck's had
a turn for the better, lads.
Don't think Drago
has one of those...
in his dragon army.
Dragon army?
Look, we don't want any trouble.
Ha!
You should have thought of that
before you stole
all of our dragons...
and blasted our fort to bits!
(TRAPPERS TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
What are you talking about?
You think we did this?
(SCOFFS) Dragon trapping
is hard enough work
as it is without
do-gooder dragon riders...
sneaking in to rescue them.
What do-gooder?
There are other dragon riders?
You mean other than your
thieving friend from last night?
You tell me.
You may have an ice-spitting
dragon on your side...
but we still have
a quota to fill.
How do you suppose we explain
this mess to Drago Bludvist?
Drago what-fist? Does
anything you say make sense?
He's expecting a new shipment of
dragons for his army by tomorrow.
And Drago don't
take well to excuses.
This is what he gave me...
last time I showed up
empty-handed.
He promised to be far less
understanding in the future.
All right, look, we don't know
anything about a dragon thief...
or an ice-spitting
dragon...
or your lunatic boss
and his dragon army, okay?
Just give us back our
dragon and we'll go...
strange, hostile person
whom we've never met.
Oh, where are my manners?
(CHUCKLES)
I'm Eret...
son of Eret.
Finest dragon trapper alive.
After all,
it's not just anyone who
can capture a Night Fury.
(SNARLS) And this is Toothless.
He says we're going. Now.
(LAUGHS)
They all say that.
Rush 'em, lads!
(TRAPPERS SHOUTING)
(TRAPPERS EXCLAIMING FEARFULLY)
Stormfly!
Come on!
Go! Go!
You will never hold on
to those dragons...
you hear me?
Drago is coming for them all!
FISHLEGS: Come on, Meatlug!
TUFFNUT: Whoo-hoo!
RUFFNUT: Yahoo!
(DRAGONS CHITTERING)
SNOTLOUT: Whoa!
(GASPS)
(ALL LAUGHING)
MAN: Hey, there, Stoick!
Hey, how are you?
Beautiful day.
Hello, Spitelout. Great race.
(SPITELOUT GRUMBLES)
Oh, sorry, Mrs. Ack.
Any sign of him?
Ah! He's probably flown off
the edge of the world by now.
Are you sure you want that
kid running the village?
You can still
delay your retirement.
He's ready. You'll see.
(DRAGONS SCREECH)
(LAUGHS)
There he is! Huh?
The pride of Berk!
Who finally decided
to show up for work. Yay.
Sorry. Got held up.
Hey, Dad, could I have a word?
Something you're
itching to tell me?
Not quite the itch you're
thinking of, but yes.
Good man!
Now, lesson one.
A chief's first duty is
to his people, so... 41?
Can we just talk in private?
Forty...
That's me! That's me! I'm next!
If we could just talk...
Excuse me.
I have been here all day.
Okay, okay. I want one
of those high seaters...
with lots of spikes and a
big stowage compartment.
Absolutely.
You got it, sir.
Dad, this is actually
a little more important
than building saddles.
Lesson two.
No task is too small
when it comes to
serving your people.
Excuse us, Grump.
Dad, can we just talk...
GOBBER: Grump!
You let the forge
die down again!
(ALL GASP)
GOBBER: That's it, Grump.
You're going up for adoption.
There you go.
Go on. Have away.
Seriously, I really
need to tell you
about this new
land we came across.
Another one?
Any new dragons?
We didn't stick
around to find out.
These folks weren't
particularly friendly.
Oh, really? Your Night
Fury and Deadly Nadder
didn't bring them
cheering to the rooftops?
No, this was different.
Not the standard run-for-the-hills
hoo-ha I've come to enjoy.
These guys were trappers.
Dragon trappers.
You should have seen their fort.
All blown apart and stuck in giant
spikes of ice. It was weird!
I've never seen
anything like it.
And worst of all,
they thought we did it!
You two are gonna get yourselves
in serious trouble
one of these days.
Not everyone appreciates
this way of life.
Aye, Gobber's right, son.
Best we keep to our own.
Besides, you'll have more
important uses for your time.
(CHUCKLES)
Once we make
the big announcement!
They are building a dragon army.
Or at least
the guy they work for is.
Dargo Bloody Fist, or something.
I'll bloody his fist with my face
if he tries to take my dragon!
Or mine!
(GROANS) You're such a moron.
A beautiful moron.
Yeah.
(GROANS)
Bludvist?
Drago Bludvist?
Yeah. Wait.
You know him?
Ground all dragons!
HICCUP: What? Why?
STOICK: Seal the gates!
Lower the storm doors!
Wait! What is happening?
GOBBER: Come on!
You heard the man!
Lock it down.
STOICK: No dragon or Viking sets foot
off this island until I give the word!
Wait, because some guy you
knew is stirring up trouble...
in some faraway land?
Because Drago Bludvist
is a madman...
without conscience or mercy.
And if he's built a dragon
army, gods help us all.
Get them into their pens!
Quickly!
Then, let's ride back out there.
We'll follow those
trappers to Drago
and talk some sense into him.
No. We fortify the island.
It's our duty to keep the peace!
Peace is over, Hiccup.
I must prepare you for war.
War?
Dad, if Drago is
coming for our dragons...
we can't wait around
for him to get here.
Let's go find him
and change his mind.
No, some minds won't
be changed, Hiccup.
Berk is what you
need to worry about.
A chief protects his own.
STOICK: Secure the stables!
Latch every stall!
Hiccup, don't!
I have to.
STOICK: This way!
Quickly!
(TOOTH LESS SCREECHES)
STOICK: Hiccup!
(PEOPLE SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
Come on!
Hiccup!
(SIGHS)
Keep your eyes peeled, lads!
With this wind, we'll reach
Drago by daybreak...
so best we fill this ship up
with dragons, and quick!
It's no time to be picky.
Eret?
Not if we want to keep our...
...heads!
Off the port quarter!
Net them, lads!
Take them down!
You're not
getting away this time.
Fire!
Reload!
TRAPPER: Reload! Incoming!
ERET: And here I was...
worried we might
turn up empty-handed.
Nope.
It's your lucky day.
(GASPS) We give up.
That's one Night Fury,
one Deadly Nadder...
and two of the finest
dragon riders west of Luk Tuk.
That ought to make
the boss happy, right?
(GROWLS) Excuse us.
ASTRID: (WHISPERS)
What are you doing?
Toothless, stay.
Uh, the dragons don't
care for cramped spaces,
so they'll just
hang out with you.
They won't be any trouble.
(TRAPPERS SNARL)
Unless you do that.
You know, wooden boat, big ocean.
How is your swimming?
Not good.
(SIGHS)
(ALL GASP)
Oops! Almost forgot. You
can't have armed prisoners.
How is this a plan?
Just what every
dragon trapper needs.
One end coats the blade
in Monstrous Nightmare saliva.
The other sprays
Hideous Zippleback gas.
All it takes is a spark, and...
(EXPLOSION)
(TRAPPERS YELL)
HICCUP: Oh, yeah, there you go.
(TRAPPERS COUGHING)
HICCUP: Once they see you
as one of their own...
even the testiest
dragons can be trained.
Right, bud?
Give me that!
(GRUNTS)
What game are you playing?
HICCUP: No game.
We just wanna meet Drago.
(GRUNTS) Why?
Because I'm going to change
his mind about dragons.
(TRAPPERS LAUGHING)
He can be really persuasive.
Once you've
earned his loyalty...
there is nothing
a dragon won't do for you.
(BLOWS RASPBERRY) You won't be
changing any minds around here.
I can change yours.
Right here. Right now.
May I?
Dragon riders!
(SNARLS)
Huh?
HICCUP: Put me down!
Snotlout, what are you doing?
See how well I
protect and provide?
(GROANS)
(GASPS) What is
with all the nets?
RUFFNUT: Hey, watch it!
That was...
close.
Oh, my.
Me likey.
Take me.
(GRUNTS)
Hold your fire!
(GRUNTS) What are you
guys doing here?
We're here to rescue you!
I don't need to be rescued!
STOICK: Enough!
Well, didn't you just
pick the wrong ship?
I am Eret,
son of (MUFFLED) Eret.
(GRUNTS) I'm...
(STRAINING)
Get this thing off me.
Anyone else?
(ERET GRUNTING)
That's what I figured.
You, saddle up.
We're going home.
No.
Of all the irresponsible...
I'm trying to protect our
dragons and stop a war!
How is that irresponsible?
Because war is
what he wants, son!
(SIGHS)
Years ago, there was a great
gathering of chieftains...
to discuss the dragon
scourge we all faced.
Into our midst came a stranger
from a strange land...
covered in scars and draped
in a cloak of dragon skin.
He carried no weapon...
and spoke softly,
saying that he...
Drago Bludvist,
was a man of the people...
devoted to freeing mankind
from the tyranny of dragons.
He claimed that he alone
could control the dragons...
and that he alone
could keep us safe...
if we chose to bow down...
and follow him.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Stupid.
Good one.
Aye, we laughed, too.
Until he wrapped himself in
his cloak and cried out...
"Then see how well
you do without me!"
The rooftop suddenly
burst into flames...
and from it,
armored dragons descended...
burning the hall to the ground.
I...
was the only one to escape.
Men who kill without reason
cannot be reasoned with.
Maybe.
Hiccup!
HICCUP: I'm still going to try.
This is what I'm good at.
And if I could
change your mind...
I can change his, too.
Come on.
Let's go.
STOICK: No!
Lead the others back to Berk.
I've had enough
mutiny for one day.
Oh, I like that.
STOICK: Ruffnut!
(GROANS) Okay!
Ah!
(GRUNTING)
Ugh!
(SCREAMS IN FRUSTRATION)
(SIGHS) Don't worry, bud.
I'm not gonna let
anything happen to you.
I promise.
(TOOTHLESS GRUMBLES)
Oh, come on, Dad!
Really?
Okay.
No sudden moves.
(DRAGON SCREECHING)
Hold on. Hold on.
(GRUNTS)
Toothless!
(GROWLING)
Hey! You left my
dragon back there!
He can't fly on his own!
He will drown!
(PANTING)
(HICCUP GRUNTS)
Hey!
Uh, we have to head
back for my dragon!
(GROWLING)
(DRAGONS GROANING)
Who are you?
The dragon thief?
Uh...
Drago Bludvist?
Do you even understand
what I'm saying?
(SCREECHES)
Toothless! It's okay,
it's okay, it's okay.
I'm glad to see you, too, bud.
You really had
me worried, there.
Uh...
(GASPING)
(MUFFLED) Hiccup?
Uh...
Could it be?
After all these years?
How is this possible?
Uh, should I...
Should I know you?
No, you were only a babe.
But a mother never forgets.
(INHALES SHARPLY)
(SHUSHING)
Come.
STOICK: Boar-headed!
Just like his mother!
Aye, she could
never stay put either.
GOBBER: He's just twenty.
And a Viking. Could there
be a worse combination?
When I think of how stubborn and
senseless you were back in the day...
Oh.
Well, not much
has changed, actually.
(SIGHS) Ah, you know
what he's like.
He won't give up, Gobber.
And if Hiccup finds Drago,
before we find him...
Nothing can hurt Hiccup...
so long as that Night Fury's around.
It's a Night Fury!
Huh?
(GRUNTS)
Find them, Skullcrusher.
Find them.
(ROARS)
Hold on.
Wait just a minute.
This way!
Come back here!
Come.
You can't just say something
like that and run off!
You're my mother?
I mean, what the...
Do you grasp how
insane it sounds?
Come, quickly!
I have questions!
(GRUNTS)
Where have you
been all this time?
What have you been doing?
But they said you were dead!
Everyone thinks
you were eaten by...
(DRAGONS SCREECHING)
(GASPS)
(DRAGON SNORTING)
This is where you've
been for 20 years?
You've been rescuing them.
Unbelievable.
You're not upset?
What? No. (STAMMERING)
I don't know.
It's a bit much to get my
head around, to be frank.
It's not every
day you find out...
your mother is some
kind of crazy, feral,
vigilante dragon lady.
Oh. (CHUCKLES)
At least I'm not boring, right?
I suppose there is
that one specific thing.
Do you like it?
(STUTTERING)
I don't have the words.
(SNIFFING)
(VALKA LAUGHS)
Can I...
Oh, he's beautiful.
(GIGGLING)
Incredible!
He might very well
be the last of his kind.
And look, he's your age.
Wow.
No wonder you get along so well.
(SPEAKING GIBBERISH)
(GASPS) And retractable teeth!
How did you manage to...
I found him in the woods.
He was shot down and wounded.
This Snafflefang lost his leg to one
of Drago Bludvist's iron traps.
This Raincutter had her wing
sliced by razor netting.
And this poor Hobblegrunt...
was blinded by a tree snare...
and then left to
die alone and scared.
And what of this?
Did Drago or his
trappers do this, too?
HICCUP: (CHUCKLES
NERVOUSLY) Oh, yeah...
The crazy thing is...
I'm actually the one
who shot him down.
Hey, it's okay, though.
He got me back!
Right, bud?
You couldn't save
all of me, could you?
You just had to make it even.
So, peg leg!
(LAUGHS)
What did your father think
of your Night Fury friend?
He didn't take it all that well.
But then he changed.
They all did.
Pretty soon, everyone back
home had dragons of their own.
If only it were possible.
No, really.
Believe me, I tried, as well...
but people are not
capable of change, Hiccup.
Some of us were
just born different.
(DRAGONS SCREECHING)
(PEOPLE SHOUTING)
MAN: Hoist the torches!
VALKA: Berk was a land of
"kill-or-be-killed"...
but I believed
peace was possible.
(STOICK YELLING)
Stop! You'll only
make it worse!
VALKA: It was a very
unpopular opinion.
(STOICK YELLING) (GASPS) Hiccup!
VALKA: Then, one night, a
dragon broke into our house...
finding you in the cradle.
(GASPS)
I rushed to protect you.
(BABY HICCUP GIGGLING)
But what I saw...
was proof of
everything I believed.
(CRYING)
(GASPING)
This wasn't a vicious beast...
but an intelligent,
gentle creature...
whose soul...
reflected my own.
(STOICK GRUNTS)
(VALKA GASPS)
STOICK: Valka, run!
VALKA: No! Don't!
Hold on!
(GRUNTS)
VALKA: No! Stoick!
STOICK: Valka!
VALKA: Stoick!
Valka.
VALKA: You and your father
nearly died that night...
all because I couldn't
kill a dragon.
It runs in the family.
It broke my heart
to stay away...
but I believed you would
be safer if I did.
How did you survive?
Oh, Cloudjumper never
meant to harm me.
He must have thought
I belonged here.
In the home of
the great Bewilderbeast.
The alpha species.
One of the very
few that still exist.
Every nest has its queen...
but this is
the king of all dragons.
With his icy breath, this
graceful giant built our nest.
A safe haven for
dragons everywhere.
Wait,
that's the ice-spitter?
He's responsible for
all that destruction?
He protects us.
We all live under his care
and his command.
(YOUNG DRAGONS CHITTERING)
VALKA: All but the babies,
of course...
...who listen to no one!
(VALKA LAUGHING)
I've lived among them...
for 20 years, Hiccup...
discovering their secrets.
(LAUGHS)
He likes you.
Wow.
You must be hungry.
Uh. Yeah, I could eat.
Good.
It's feeding time.
I don't like it.
They should have been
back with Hiccup by now.
I don't like it either.
Eret, son of Eret...
was the man of my dreams.
My everything!
But, baby,
I grew facial hair for you.
Me, too.
What if Drago shot them down?
What if they need our help?
We have to find them.
Wait, what?
No, but Stoick said...
It doesn't matter what he said,
if they have all been captured.
Come on!
TRAPPER: Do we go back?
ERET: We have nowhere to
go, nothing to sell...
and no heads to call our own!
If we don't turn up with
dragons, and fast... (SCREAMS)
Careful what you wish for!
UG: Eret, son of Eret!
What is this?
A kidnapping.
Yay! Can he ride with me?
Can he? (HUSKILY) Can he?
ERET: Ugh!
You're gonna show
us the way to Drago.
And help dragon riders sneak into
Drago's camp? Just kill me now.
That could be arranged.
Stormfly, drop it!
Huh? (SCREAMS)
Good girl!
Stormfly, fetch!
ERET: (SCREAMING)
All right!
Okay! I'll take
you to Drago!
Works every time.
(ERET PANTING)
(DRAGONS SCREECHING)
Hey, I thought we
were going to eat.
Oh, we are.
(BELLOWING)
(GASPS)
(LAUGHING)
Then, from Dragon Island...
I found this archipelago.
VALKA: There.
(SIGHS) Whoa!
(TOOTH LESS GROANS)
(CHUCKLES)
Whoo-hoo!
(LAUGHING)
VALKA: Oh,
when I'm up here...
I don't even feel the cold.
I just feel...
Free.
(INHALES) This is what it
is to be a dragon, Hiccup.
It's all well and good
to call yourself a dragon...
but can you fly?
(GASPS)
(LAUGHS)
(WHOOPING)
Oh, no!
Ha! (LAUGHS)
(WHOOPING)
Man! Almost!
We just about had it that time!
(GRUNTS)
(SPITS)
Incredible.
Well, not bad yourself.
All this time,
you took after me.
And where was I?
I'm so sorry, Hiccup.
Can we start over?
Will you give me another chance?
I can teach you all that I have
learned these past 20 years.
Like...
(MOANS)
Wow.
Now you can make
those tight turns.
Did you know about this?
Every dragon has its secrets.
And I'll show them all to you.
We'll unlock every mystery...
find every last
species together...
as mother and son.
(LAUGHING)
This gift we share,
Hiccup, it bonds us.
This is who you are, son.
Who we are.
We will change the world
for all dragons.
We will make it a better,
safer place.
Yeah.
That sounds amazing.
(SIGHS)
This is so great!
Now you and I can
go talk to Drago together.
What?
There's no talking to Drago.
But we have to...
No.
We must protect our own.
Come on,
we should be getting back.
Hmm?
(ERET GRUNTS)
Okay! Look, I got you here.
Now get this thing off me.
Never take a toy from a dragon.
Don't you know anything?
(ERET GROANS)
Why does this
keep happening to me?
(MEN SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
What's down there?
Large diameter bubbles,
massive lungs...
cold water deep dweller.
I'm thinking class five
leviathan, maybe six.
(GROWLS)
(YELLS)
(GROANING)
(MEN SHOUTING)
FISHLEGS: Meatlug!
What's wrong, girl?
(MEN SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
ERET: Drago!
(GROANS)
Get off me!
ERET: (CHUCKLES) Always great
to see you, my friend!
Keeping warm up here?
As you can see,
I'm right on time
with a new batch of dragons...
just like I promised.
MAN: He's waking up!
Give me some backup, here!
Drop the ropes!
(SNARLS)
Huh.
(YELLING)
(GROWLING SOFTLY)
(MOANS)
SNOTLOUT: Hookfang!
RUFFNUT: Hey!
What are you doing?
You belong to me now.
(MEN LAUGHING)
ERET: And as
an added bonus...
I also caught you their riders.
No extra charge.
What?
Are you kidding me?
Aw!
But you were so perfect!
Turns out, there is a whole
bunch of them out there.
(CHOKING)
How many?
Drago doesn't
have them after all.
How many?
ASTRID: Hundreds.
A whole island full!
(COUGHING) I wouldn't
worry about it.
(CHOKING) My men are hunting
them down as we speak.
They won't know where you're
hiding, I promise you that.
Yes, they will.
They know we're missing...
and they have tracking dragons.
If you so much as touch us,
Hiccup is gonna kick...
Hiccup?
ERET: (RASPILY) He's not a problem.
Really. Trust me.
He's only the son
of Stoick the Vast,
his heir to
the throne of Berk...
and the greatest dragon master
this world has ever seen!
Dragon master?
I alone control the dragons!
No. Mmm-mmm.
Sorry.
And unless you let
us go, right now...
he will blast through here
on his Night Fury...
and blow your entire fleet
of ships to splinters.
Then they will be
crying like babies.
(BOYS LAUGHING)
Funny and beautiful.
Good one, babe!
(RUFFNUT GROANS) Like
babies, they always cry.
Real tiny ones.
First, there was one rider,
and now, all of Berk.
And you led them to me!
(GRUNTS) Drago!
Stop all preparations!
We must attack the dragon
riders' nest at once!
We will take down their alpha!
Then we will take Berk!
(MEN CHEERING)
Drago.
And get rid of him.
Oh, Drago, please, I...
ASTRID: Stormfly!
Hmm.
No! (GRUNTS)
(DRAGONS SCREECHING)
Well, bud, we can't wait around
for Drago to attack this place.
We've gotta find him first.
(GROWLS)
(CHOMPING)
Let's go.
(MUFFLED GASP)
Easy now.
Are you kidding me?
How did you get in here?
The same way we
are getting you out.
We?
All clear.
Toothless, come.
Wait. There's something
you need to know.
STOICK: Yeah, yeah,
tell me on the way.
This isn't an on-the-way
kind of update, actually.
I've heard enough.
More of the
earth-shattering-development variety.
Yeah, just add it to the pile.
(HICCUP STUTTERING)
Dad, unlike most surprises I spring
on you, this is one you'll like.
I promise.
You just have to
handle it delicately.
You might want to take this one.
Huh?
Oh, boy.
Oh. Uh...
Dad...
could you put
the sword away, please?
(GASPS)
Oh.
(SWORD CLANGS)
I know what you're
gonna say, Stoick.
How could I have done this?
Stayed away all of these years?
And why did I not
come back to you?
To our son?
What sign did I have that
you could change, Stoick?
That anyone on Berk could?
I pleaded so many times
to stop the fighting...
to find another answer,
but did any of you listen?
This is why I never married.
This and one other reason.
I know that I left you
to raise Hiccup alone...
but I thought he would be
better off without me.
And I was wrong,
I see that now, but...
Oh!
Stop being so stoic, Stoick!
Go on.
Shout, scream, say something!
You're as beautiful
as the day I lost you.
(DRAGONS SNUFFLING)
(DRAGO GRUNTS)
SNOTLOUT: Could this
day get any worse?
TUFFNUT: Let me see.
We're gonna jump into freezing cold
water, and then die from drowning.
ERET: Looks refreshing.
Please, ladies first.
You are a steaming
heap of dragon...
Duck.
(MEN GRUNT)
Warn the others!
Get them, you son of an Eret.
(MEN GRUNTING)
TUFFNUT: Take that!
(MAN GROANING)
Okay, I love you again.
(EXHALES) Pathetic.
You can still jump.
So, are we going to save your dragons
and get out of here, or not?
Hmm.
ERET: Check every trap.
They're here somewhere.
(GRUNTING)
Meatlug?
(GROANS)
(STRAINING) Anyone coming?
I don't know. You just keep
doing what you are doing.
Keep cranking.
(GRUNTS)
Thank you for saving my life.
(GURGLES)
Now let me return the favor.
Mom, you'd never
even recognize it.
Where we used to make weapons, we
now build saddles, wing-slings.
We even fix dragon teeth!
You wouldn't believe how
much everything's changed.
Our son has changed
Berk for the better.
I think we did well
with this one, Val.
Thanks, Dad.
Oh!
STOICK: (CHUCKLES)
Oh, I got it. I got it.
(WHIMPERS)
(RETCHING)
I'm a little out of practice.
Well, you know...
I didn't marry you for your cooking.
GOBBER: I hope not.
Her meatballs could kill more
beasts than a battle-axe.
I've still got a few knocking
around in here. (LAUGHS)
And once you move back in,
with all your dragons...
Drago won't even stand a chance.
Everything will be okay!
Slow down, son.
It's a lot to take in.
HICCUP: Oh, gotcha.
(STOICK WHISTLING)
Oh, I love this one.
(CONTINUES WHISTLING)
Remember our song, Val?
(SINGING) I'll swim and
sail on savage seas
With ne'er a fear of drowning
And gladly ride
the waves of life
If you will marry me
No scorching sun
Nor freezing cold Will stop...
Will stop me on my journey
Sorry. (CHUCKLES)
(EXHALES)
If you will
promise me your heart
And love...
(SIGHS)
And love me for eternity
My dearest one
My darling dear
Your mighty words astound me
But I've no need of mighty deeds
When I feel your arms around me
But I would bring
you rings of gold
I'd even sing you poetry
Whoo!
Oh, would you?
And I would keep
you from all harm
If you would stay beside me
I have no use for rings of gold
I care not for your poetry
I only want your hand to hold
I only want you near me
STOICK AND VALKA: To love
and kiss, to sweetly hold
For the dancing and the dreaming
Through all life's
sorrows and delights
I'll keep your love inside me
I will swim and
sail on savage seas
With ne'er a fear of drowning
And gladly ride
the waves of life
If you will marry me
(BOTH LAUGHING)
(GOBBER VOCALIZING)
I'm still going
Gobber!
I'm done.
(SIGHS)
(LAUGHS)
I thought I would have to die before
we could have that dance again.
No need for drastic measures.
For you, my dear...
anything.
Will you come home, Val?
Will you be my wife once again?
(GASPS)
(BOTH LAUGH)
We can be a family!
What do you say?
Oh...
Yes.
Great!
I'll do the cooking.
Thank Odin you
didn't listen to me, son.
We never would
have found each other.
(DRAGONS SHRIEKING)
Toothless?
What's happening?
(GROANS)
(PEOPLE CLAMORING)
(EXHALES SHARPLY)
(EXPLOSIONS)
Oh, no.
Val?
Val! It's all right,
it's all right.
We're a team now.
What do you want to do?
We have to save the dragons.
Aye. You got it!
Come on, son.
(MEN CLAMORING)
Whatever comes,
keep hitting the mountain.
We need to draw the alpha out.
Ready the traps!
(MAN GRUNTING)
(GASPS)
TUFFNUT: Surprise!
Yeah! (SNICKERING)
What?
Whoa!
Whoo! Whoo-hoo!
You really are
full of surprises!
(GRUNTS) Let's go!
TUFFNUT: Dragon riders,
coming through!
Fire!
(TUFFNUT LAUGHING)
Yeah!
Cut them down!
Ah! Whoa, whoa, whoa!
RUFFNUT: Eret, son of Eret!
(SCREAMING)
ASTRID: Up, girl!
Lean left, Eret!
That's it!
(ERET SHOUTS)
ASTRID: Look out!
(ERET GRUNTING)
HICCUP: Yeah, baby!
Take them down!
Heads up!
(ALL GRUNTING)
(CHUCKLES)
Dragon master.
Welcome aboard, dragon rider!
Thanks, I think.
Where have you been?
Oh, you know,
catching up with Mom.
(GASPS)
(ROARING)
That's your mother?
Now you know where I
get my dramatic flair.
The alpha!
Now we have a fight!
(ROARING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
(SCREECHING)
HICCUP: Come on,
Toothless!
Show them what you got, bud.
(WHOOPING)
That a boy!
(GASPS)
(GRUNTING)
(DRAGO SNICKERING)
I've waited
a long time for this!
You cannot take our dragons!
They are controlled
by the alpha!
Then it's a good thing
I brought a challenger.
(GRUNTS)
(SHOUTING)
(CHAINS RATTLING)
(GROWLING)
Another one?
FISHLEGS: That is a class ten!
Class ten!
(ALL SCREAMING)
VALKA: No.
DRAGO: Come on!
Take down the alpha!
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(CHOKING)
(GASPS)
(SHOUTING)
(STOICK GRUNTING)
(GROANS)
Thank you.
For you, my dear...
anything. (GRUNTS)
(BOTH ROARING)
Val, do you think
you can stop them?
I'll do my best.
Come on, Cloudjumper!
You!
I watched you burn!
It takes more than a
little fire to kill me!
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(GASPS)
Stoick!
(GROWLING)
No!
(ROARING)
We have won.
Now, finish her!
No!
(DRAGO'S BEWILDERBEAST ROARING)
(VALKA GROANS)
STOICK: Hold on!
Skullcrusher, go!
Come on, Gobber!
Right behind you, Stoick!
(SCREAMS)
Whoa! Whoa!
(SCREAMING)
(BOTH GRUNT)
HICCUP: Stop!
Stop!
(SNICKERING)
This is the great dragon master?
The son of Stoick the Vast?
What shame he must feel.
All of this loss, and for what?
To become unstoppable?
To rule the world?
Dragons are kind,
amazing creatures...
that can bring people together.
Or tear them apart.
(GASPS)
You see...
I know what it is
to live in fear.
To see my village burned...
my family taken.
But even as a boy...
left with nothing...
I vowed to rise above
the fear of dragons...
and liberate
the people of this world.
Then why a dragon army?
Well, you need dragons
to conquer other dragons.
Or maybe you need dragons
to conquer people.
To control those
who follow you...
and to get rid of
those who won't.
(SNICKERING)
Clever boy.
The world wants peace.
And we have the answer
back on Berk.
Just let me show you.
No!
Let me show you!
(SHOUTING)
What in...
Hiccup!
(PANTING) STOICK: Come on, Gobber!
Okay, change of plan!
No dragon can resist
the alpha's command.
So, he who controls the alpha...
controls them all.
Toothless?
(WHIMPERS)
Toothless, you okay, bud?
What's going on?
DRAGO: Witness true strength.
The strength of
will over others.
In the face of it...
you are nothing.
What did he just tell you?
(PANTING)
Toothless, come on.
What's the matter with you?
No, no, no, no.
Come on.
What are you doing?
Knock it off.
Stop! Snap out of it!
(GRUNTING)
Toothless, no!
Toothless!
HICCUP: Don't!
Hiccup!
Stop!
Son!
Dad!
No!
(GASPING)
Hmm.
(PANTING)
No.
(GRUNTING)
Dad!
Stoick!
Dad.
No, you...
No.
HICCUP: No, no, no.
(GASPS)
No! Get away from him!
(WHINES)
Go on! Get out of here!
(WHIMPERS)
HICCUP: Get away!
It's not his fault.
You know that.
(SIGHS)
(ROARING)
VALKA: Good dragons...
under the control
of bad people...
Wait! Don't go.
VALKA: ...do bad things.
(SNICKERS)
(GRUNTS)
(TOOTHLESS WHIMPERS)
DRAGO: Come on!
Gather the men
and meet me at Berk!
Toothless!
No, don't.
(MEN CHEERING)
(GROWLS)
GOBBER: May the Valkyries
welcome you...
and lead you through
Odin's great battlefield.
May they sing your name
with love and fury...
so that we might hear it rise
from the depths of Valhalla...
and know that you have taken
your rightful place...
at the table of kings.
For a great man has fallen.
A warrior.
A Chieftain.
A father.
A friend.
I'm sorry, Dad.
(SIGHS)
(SNIFFLING)
I'm not the chief
that you wanted me to be.
And I'm not the peacekeeper
I thought I was.
I don't know...
(SIGHS)
You came early into this world.
You were such a wee thing.
So frail, so fragile.
I feared you wouldn't make it.
But your father...
he never doubted.
He always said
you would become
the strongest of them all.
And he was right.
You have the heart of a chief
and a soul of a dragon.
Only you can bring
our worlds together.
That is who you are, son.
I, uh...
I was so afraid
of becoming my dad.
Mostly because I
thought I never could.
How do you become
someone that great?
That brave?
That selfless?
I guess you can only try.
A chief protects his own.
We are going back.
Uh, with what?
He took all the dragons.
Not all of them.
(ALL SCREAMING)
FISHLEGS: I don't want to die!
We can't fly these things!
FISHLEGS: Yeah, no kidding!
(GRUNTS) Whoa!
(YELLING)
But won't that
Bewilderbeast just
take control of these guys, too?
They're babies.
They don't listen to anyone.
Yeah! Just like us!
This is very dangerous!
(GOBBER SCREAMS)
Some might suggest
this is poorly conceived.
It's a good thing
that I never listen.
So what is your plan?
Get Toothless back
and kick Drago's...
Heads up!
And that thing.
Whoa... Ow!
(RUMBLING)
(ROARING)
(SNORING)
(SQUAWKING)
(GASPS)
(EXCLAIMING HAPPILY)
That's a good boy.
(COOING)
(STAMMERS) Watch the furniture!
Where are you going?
(GASPS)
(PEOPLE SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
(ROARING)
(ALL GASP)
Your chief is dead.
Stoick?
No one can protect you now.
(ROARING)
(GASPS)
HICCUP: No.
He took all the dragons!
Distract the alpha. Try to
keep his focus off Toothless.
Uh... How?
Have you forgotten
who you're riding with?
There isn't a dragon alive
that I can't wrangle!
Except for this one!
Amateur.
Hey, look.
It's Hiccup!
(ALL CHEERING)
What?
(BLEATING)
RUFFNUT: (GRUNTS)
Keep them coming!
Black sheep, baby!
(ROARING)
(BLEATING)
SNOTLOUT: Ten points!
(ALL LAUGHING)
Oh-oh.
(GIGGLING)
(GROWLS)
(GASPS)
FISHLEGS: I'm okay!
(EXHALES)
You certainly are hard to
get rid of, I'll say that.
Toothless?
Hey...
it's me, bud.
It's me.
I'm right here, bud.
Come back to me.
(DRAGO LAUGHS)
He's not yours anymore.
He belongs to the alpha.
But, please,
great dragon master...
try to take him.
He will not miss a second time.
It wasn't your fault, bud.
They made you do it.
You would never hurt him.
(DISTORTED)
You would never hurt me.
(TOOTHLESS COOING)
How are you doing that?
Please.
You are my best friend, bud.
(GROWLING SOFTLY)
My best friend.
Atta boy! That's it!
I'm here!
DRAGO: Enough!
(GRUNTS)
(EXCLAIMS)
Hang on!
(DRAGO SCREAMING)
(GRUNTS)
Almost there, buddy.
DRAGO: Do something!
We need to get those two apart.
We have to block
him out, Toothless.
Do you trust me, bud?
(RUMBLES)
We can do this.
You and me.
As one.
That's it.
Now let's try
this one more time!
(ALL CHEERING)
Take him down, babe!
Go get them!
Take control of it!
Shut it out, Toothless.
Stop them!
Now!
(LAUGHING)
(GASPS)
(GRUNTING)
(SCREAMS)
(GROANING)
Not again.
Toothless!
It's now or never!
Come on, bud!
(GRUNTS)
Hold on!
Yeah! We did it!
(GRUNTS)
(SHOUTS)
HICCUP: Hold him there,
Toothless.
It's all over now.
Or is it?
Uh...
Oh, no!
(SCREAMS)
(CHUCKLES)
No!
(GRUNTING)
Hiccup!
(ICE CRACKING)
(GASPS)
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
(ROARING)
(PANTING)
He's challenging the alpha!
To protect you.
(ROARS)
No, no, no! No!
Fight back! Fight!
Fight!
What's the matter with you?
(PEOPLE MURMURING)
Now do you get it?
This is what it is to
earn a dragon's loyalty.
(PANTS)
Let this end. Now.
Never!
Come on!
(ROARS)
Ah! (GRUNTS)
Fight!
(YELLS)
(BELLOWING)
(ROARING)
(GROANING)
The alpha protects them all.
(GRUNTING)
(ALL CHEERING)
(CHEERING CONTINUES)
(ROARS)
(ALL ROARING)
(PEOPLE CHEERING)
You never cease
to amaze me, bud.
Thank you.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Toothless, you know
that doesn't wash out!
MAN: I knew
you'd come back!
ASTRID: Stormfly!
(LAUGHS)
Oh, give me a cuddle, Grumpy!
(GROANS)
(CHUCKLES)
Who's my little princess?
Don't you ever
leave again, Hookfang.
You are! Yes, you are!
I missed you!
Oh, Barf!
Not you!
That was some pretty fine
dragon wrangling back there.
You'd make a good trapper.
Whoa! (CHUCKLES)
You know, Skullcrusher's
gonna need somebody
to look after him now.
Me?
I'd be honored.
Your father would be
every bit as proud as I am.
(CHUCKLES) Thank you.
I'm really glad
you're here, Mom.
And here I'll stay.
See?
I told you it was in here.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Still doing that one?
That's hilarious.
Come here, you.
Mmm.
Ooh!
The chief has come home!
(ALL CHEERING)
ALL: (CHANTING)
Long live the chief!
SNOTLOUT: (EXCLAIMING) Yeah!
(GRUNTS)
Ah. (GASPS)
(SNOTLOUT EXCLAIMING)
(ALL CHEERING)
HICCUP: This is Berk.
A bit trampled and busted
and covered in ice...
but it's home.
It's our home.
(PEOPLE TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
HICCUP: Those who attacked us
are relentless and crazy.
But those who stopped them...
oh, even more so!
(ASTRID LAUGHING)
HICCUP: We may be
small in numbers...
but we stand for something...
bigger than anything
the world can pit against us.
We are the voice of peace.
And, bit by bit,
we will change this world.
(SHEEP BLEATING)
(GASPS)
HICCUP: You see, we have
something they don't.
Oh, sure, they have armies...
and they have armadas...
but we have...
our dragons!
(ROARS)
(SINGING) Let the wind carry us
To the clouds,
hurry up, all right
We can travel so far
As our eyes can see
We go where no one goes
We slow for no one
Get out...
...of our way
Awake in the sky
We break up so high, all right
Let's make it our own
Let's savor it
We go where no one goes
We slow for no one
Get out of our way
We go where no one goes
We slow for no one